Guide to the Hermann Broch Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-86; Series I; 7.5; (20 boxes)
  - CORRESPONDENCE OF KAHLER FAMILY
    - Rogers, Frances Colby, 1951-74, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 526)
    - Roth, William, 1948 Jan 13 (Box 17, Folder 527)
    - Rothe, Wolfgang, 1953 Dec (Box 18, Folder 528)
    - Rothstein, Irma, 1953-54, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 529)
    - Sahl, Hans, 1951 Jun 9 (Box 18, Folder 530)
    - Sauerländer, Wolfgang, 1941 Jul 11 (Box 18, Folder 531)
    - Scharl, Josef, 1951 Jun 6 (Box 18, Folder 532)
    - Schlant, Ernestine, 1986 Jun 8 (Box 18, Folder 533)
    - Schöler, Esther, 1952-55 (Box 18, Folder 534)
    - Schreiber, Carl F., 1952, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 535)
    - Seitz, Bruno and Anna, 1974-81 (Box 18, Folder 536)
    - Sessions, Roger, 1951 Jun 19 (Box 18, Folder 537)
    - Steiner, George, 1963, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 538)
    - Sterba, Richard, 1951 Jun 4 (Box 18, Folder 539)
    - Stern, Jimmy, 1951 Jun 10 (Box 18, Folder 540)
    - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1986 May 15 (Box 18, Folder 541)
    - Ungar, Robert, 1951 Jun 2 (Box 18, Folder 542)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1943-70, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 543-45)
    - Urzidil, Johannes, 1951 Jul 17 (Box 18, Folder 546)
    - Waldinger, Ernst, 1951 Jun (Box 18, Folder 547)
    - Warburg, Frederick I., 1951 (Box 18, Folder 548)
    - Weigand, Hermann John, 1952, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 549)
    - Weyl, Hermann, 1951 Jul (Box 18, Folder 550)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 551)
    - Winter, Hanns, 1951 Oct 18 (Box 18, Folder 552)
    - Wolff, Eleanor L., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 553)
    - Wolff, Kurt, 1953 Mar (Box 18, Folder 554)
    - Wysling, Hans, 1972 Dec 19 (Box 18, Folder 555)
    - Zuckerkandl, Victor and Mimi, 1943-51 (Box 18, Folder 556)
    - Unidentified, 1952-85 (Box 18, Folder 557)
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    This subseries represents third-party corres- pondence between various friends and colleagues of Hermann Broch concerning the author. The materials are usually arranged alphabetically by recipient and thereunder by sender.
    - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe
      - Pick, Robert, 1957-66 (Box 19, Folder 558)
      - Weigand, Hermann John, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 559)
    - Bródy, Dániel
      - Kaprinay, Emma von, ca. 1952 (Box 19, Folder 560)
      - Ludovyk-Gyömröi, Edith, 1951 Sep 13 (Box 19, Folder 561)
      - Pick, Robert, 1951-56 (Box 19, Folder 562-63)
    - Bunzel, Joseph
      - Bródy, Dániel, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 564)
      - Brude-Firnau, Gisela, 1971 Nov 2 (Box 19, Folder 565)
      - Kahler, Erich, 1951-68, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 566)
      - Krafft-Kennedy, Ludwig, 1951-52 (Box 19, Folder 567)
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 568)
      - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 569)
      - Weigand, Hermann John, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 570)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel and Marion Ponsonby Gause
      - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe, 1952 Feb 4 (Box 19, Folder 571)
      - Faber du Faur, Curt von, 1952 Nov 22 (Box 19, Folder 572)
      - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1951 Apr 18 (Box 19, Folder 573)
      - Krafft-Kennedy, Ludwig, 1951 Oct 30 (Box 19, Folder 574)
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 575)
      - Schreiber, Carl F., 1951 Feb 20 (Box 19, Folder 576)
      - Waldinger, Ernst, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 577)
      - Wolff, Eleanor L., 1951 Nov 23 (Box 19, Folder 578)
      - Miscellaneous, 1951-52 (Box 19, Folder 579)
    - Döblin, Alfred
      - Schwarzwald, Mrs., 1931 Feb 3 (Box 19, Folder 580)
    - Faber du Faur, Curt von
      - Lange, Victor, 1951 Sep 3 (Box 19, Folder 581)
    - Fritz-Vietta, Egon
      - Augustin, Elisabeth, 1949-50 (Box 19, Folder 582)
    - Jacobi, Jolande
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 583)
    - Johnson, Alvin Saunders
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1951 Jun 2 (Box 19, Folder 584)
      - Loewenthal, Minnie, 1951 Nov 22 (Box 19, Folder 585)
    - Kolb, Annette
      - Allesch, Emma von ("Ea"), 1931 Feb 28 (Box 19, Folder 586)
    - Levy, Edith Jonas
      - Broch, Annemarie Meier-Graefe, 1978 May 14 (Box 19, Folder 587)
      - Bródy, Daisy, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 588)
      - Haydn, Hiram, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 589)
      - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1951 Jun 2 (Box 19, Folder 590)
      - Kenton, Mr., 1951 Jun 1 (Box 19, Folder 591)
      - Schächter, Josef, 1974 Nov 21 (Box 19, Folder 592)
      - Skwara, Erich Wolfgang, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 593)
      - White, Dr., 1950 May 8 (Box 19, Folder 594)
    - Pick, Robert
      - Hermann Broch Literary Advisory Committee, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 595)
      - Krafft-Kennedy, Ludwig, 1954 Jul 28 (Box 19, Folder 596)
      - Lützeler, Paul Michael, 1971 Nov 29 (Box 19, Folder 597)
      - Wolff, Kurt, 1954 Nov 11 (Box 19, Folder 598)
      - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 599)
    - Staudinger, Hans
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1974, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 600)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr
      - Benjamin, Robert Spiers, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 601)
      - Brousseau, Jule, 1944 Jul 11 (Box 19, Folder 602)
      - Colum, Mary, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 603)
      - Johnson, Alvin Saunders, 1947 Apr 29 (Box 19, Folder 604)
      - Judd, Jadwiga, 1939-41 (Box 19, Folder 605)
      - Kahler, Antoinette, 1946-47 (Box 19, Folder 606)
      - Kauffer, E. McKnight, 1945 Sep 22 (Box 19, Folder 607)
      - Kesten, Hermann, 1943 Apr 2 (Box 19, Folder 608)
      - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1969, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 609)
      - Norden, Ruth, 1940 Nov 19 (Box 19, Folder 610)
      - Paschke, Henry, 1947 Sep (Box 19, Folder 611)
      - Polzer, Victor, 1942-43 (Box 19, Folder 612)
      - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1944 Oct 19 (Box 19, Folder 613)
      - Sachs, Hanns, 1943-45 (Box 19, Folder 614)
      - Schiff, Violet, 1945 Jul 25 (Box 19, Folder 615)
      - Schreiber, Carl F., 1946-47 (Box 19, Folder 616)
      - Staudinger, Else, 1946 Nov 13 (Box 19, Folder 617)
      - Weigand, Hermann John, 1946-47 (Box 19, Folder 618)
      - Wieck, Fred, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 619)
      - Wolff, Kurt and Helen, 1944-45 (Box 19, Folder 620)
      - Unidentified, 1945, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 621)
      - Der Tod des Vergil: JSU's translation
        - "A" general, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 622)
        - Bródy, Dániel, 1946 Aug 22 (Box 20, Folder 623)
        - "F" general, 1941-45 (Box 20, Folder 624)
        - Farano, Michel Batta, 1944-55 (Box 20, Folder 625)
        - Goll, Yvan, 1945 Aug 26 (Box 20, Folder 626)
        - Greenberg, Martin, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 627)
        - "H" general, 1945-51 (Box 20, Folder 628)
        - Haydn, Hiram, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 629)
        - Howe, Quincy, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 630)
        - "J" general, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 631)
        - "K" general, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 632)
        - Kahler family, 1944-51 (Box 20, Folder 633)
        - "L" general, 1945-51 (Box 20, Folder 634)
        - Levy, Edith Jonas, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 635)
        - "M" general, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 636)
        - MacLeish, Archibald, 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 637)
        - "P" general, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 638)
        - Pick, Robert, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 639)
        - "R" general, 1945-51, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 640)
        - "S" general, 1943-51 (Box 20, Folder 641)
        - "T" general, 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 642)
        - The Times Literary Supplement, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 643)
        - "V" general, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 644)
        - Wolff, Eleanor L., 1945 Jun 22 (Box 20, Folder 645)
        - Unidentified, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 646)
- Writings, 1913-88; Series II; 16; (39 boxes)
  Series II, Writings (Boxes 21-58), is organized into four subseries: Books, Plays, Poems, and Shorter Works. The materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - BOOKS
    - Bergroman
      Between 1935 and 1951 Broch wrote three versions of this novel, none of which was ever completed. It has been known by several names. "Bergroman" was the name Broch himself used most frequently in referring to the unfinished work. In 1953, a conflation of all three versions was edited by Felix Stössinger as Der Versucher. In 1969, all three versions along with a guide were edited by Frank Kress and Hans Albert Maier under the title Bergroman. In 1976, Paul Michael Lützeler edited the novel under the title Die Verzauberung. H. F. Broch de Rothermann's English translation, entitled The Spell (1986), was based primarily on the Lützeler edition. Other names associated with the work include Demeter and The Bewitchment.
      - First version
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 21, Folder 647-51)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (incomplete) (Box 21, Folder 652-54)
        - Variant draft, typescript, carbon (incomplete), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 655-57)
      - Second version
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 21, Folder 658-62)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 663-65)
        - Variant draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 22, Folder 666)
      - Third version
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 667-69)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 670)
      - "Demeter oder Die Verzauberung (Inhalt)" [description of versions 1 and 2 of the Mountain Novel ], draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 22, Folder 671)
      - Description of The Bewitchment (Die Verzauberung), including the English translation by Jean Starr Untermeyer, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 22, Folder 672)
      - "Vorwort [zu dem Bergroman]," including translation by Jean Starr Untermeyer, "Introduction to a Peasant Novel," draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 673)
      - Der Versucher (Stössinger)
        See also: Photographs, Box 70, folder 1760
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 22, Folder 674-79)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected (incomplete) (Box 22, Folder 680-81)
        - Book reviews, 1953-55 (Box 22, Folder 682)
      - Bergroman (Kress and Maier)
        - Book reviews, 1969-71 (Box 22, Folder 683)
      - "Doctor Barbara" (Broch de Rothermann)
        - Draft, holograph, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 684)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 685)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 686)
        - Draft, typescript, photocopies, corrected, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 687)
      - The Spell (Broch de Rothermann)
        "Foreword"
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 688)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon and photocopy, corrected, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 689)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 690-701)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 702-07)
        - Draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 708-17)
        - Draft, typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 718-19)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, with printer's annotations, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 720-31)
        - Galley proofs, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 732-34)
        - Galley proofs, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 735-37)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, with printer's annotations, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 738-43)
        - Page proofs, corrected, copy 1, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 744-51)
        - Page proofs, corrected, copy 2, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 752-59)
        - Page proofs, bound, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 760)
        - Print samples, design suggestions, etc., 1986 (Box 27, Folder 761)
        - Dust jackets
          See: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1796
        - Advertisements, 1986-89 (Box 27, Folder 762-64)
        - Book reviews, 1986-87 (Box 27, Folder 765)
    - "Filsmann"
      - Draft fragments, typescript, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 766)
    - Hofmannsthal und seine Zeit
      - List of books read by Broch while writing Hofmannsthal, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 767)
      - Chapter I
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 768-69)
        - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 770)
        - Final draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 771-72)
      - Chapter II
        - Early draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 773)
        - Middle draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 774-75)
        - Final draft, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 776)
        - Final draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 777-78)
      - Chapter III
        - First draft, typescript, corrected, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 779)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 780)
      - English translation of part of final draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 781)
      - Book reviews, 1952-85 (Box 28, Folder 782)
    - Massenpsychologie
      See: "Articles and Essays" section for related shorter works
      - Vorwort, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 783)
      - "Autobiographie als Arbeitsprogramm"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 1, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 784-86)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 2, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 787-89)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 3, incomplete, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 790)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 791)
        - Part I
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 792)
          - Draft B, typescript and carbon (incomplete) (English) (Box 29, Folder 793)
        - Part II
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 794)
          - Draft B, typescript and carbon (incomplete) (English) (Box 29, Folder 795)
      - "Geschichtsgesetz und Willensfreiheit"
        - Outline (pages 15-18 missing), holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 796)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 797-98)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 799-800)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 801)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 802)
        - English translation
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 803)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 804)
          - Draft C, typescript and carbon (Box 30, Folder 805)
      - "Gibt es noch Demokratie?"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 806-07)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 808-09)
        - Draft fragments, typescript and carbon (Box 30, Folder 810)
      - "Zur politischen Situation unserer Zeit"
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 811)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 812)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 813)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 814-16)
      - Book reviews, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 817)
    - Die Schlafwandler
      - I. Pasenow
        - Draft, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 31, Folder 818)
        - Draft, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 1 (Box 31, Folder 819)
        - Draft, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 2 (Box 31, Folder 820)
        - Page proofs, bound, corrected (Box 31, Folder 821)
        - Page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 822-24)
      - II. Esch
        - Draft A, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 825)
        - Draft A, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 32, Folder 826)
        - Draft B, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 1 (Box 32, Folder 827)
        - Draft B, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected, copy 2 (Box 32, Folder 828)
        - Page proofs, bound, corrected (Box 33, Folder 829)
        - Television dramatization
          - Advertisements, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 830)
          - Publicity, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 831)
          - Reviews, 1978-79 (Box 33, Folder 832)
      - III. Huguenau
        - Draft, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 833)
        - "Epilog"
          - Draft A, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 834)
          - Draft B, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 835)
          - Draft B, bound, typescript, corrected, carbon (Box 33, Folder 836)
          - Draft C, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 34, Folder 837)
        - "Der Roman Die Schlafwandler ," draft, typescript, carbon (Box 34, Folder 838)
        - "88. Zerfall der Werte (10) Epilog ," galley proofs, corrected, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 839)
          See also: Box 57, folders 1341-45
      - Advertisements, 1932-85 (Box 34, Folder 840)
      - Book reviews, 1931-87, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 841-45)
        See also: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1797
      - Booklet containing 14 colored pastel drawings of an infant by Emmy Ferand, 1934 (Box 34, Folder 846)
      - Scrapbook
        See: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1798
    - Die Schuldlosen
      - "Parabel von der Stimme," translation of Jean Starr Untermeyer, typescript, carbon (Box 34, Folder 847)
        See also: Box 53, folder 1227
      - "Stimmen 1913" [a.k.a. "Canto 1913"], draft, typescript and carbon (Box 34, Folder 848)
      - Chapter I, "Mit schwacher Brise segeln," draft, mimeograph (Box 34, Folder 849)
      - Chapter II, "Methodisch konstruiert" [a.k.a. "Eine methodische Novelle"]
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 850)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 851)
      - "Stimmen 1923" [a.k.a. "Canto 1923"], draft, typescript and carbon (Box 34, Folder 852)
      - Chapter III, "Verlorener Sohn" [a.k.a. "Die Heimkehr" and "Spiegelbild des Lichtes"]
        - Draft, bound, typescript (Box 34, Folder 853)
        - Die neue Rundschau: offprint, 1933 Dec (Box 34, Folder 854)
      - Chapter IV, "Ballade vom Imker," draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 855)
      - Chapter V, "Die Erzählung der Magd Zerline," English translation by Jane B. Greene, draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 856)
        See also: Box 45, folders 992-97
      - Chapter VIII, "Ballade von der Kupplerin," draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 35, Folder 857)
      - Chapter IX, "Erkaufte Mutter," draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 858)
      - "Stimmen 1933" [a.k.a. "Canto 1933"], draft, typescript and carbon (Box 35, Folder 859)
      - Chapter X, "Steinerner Gast," draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 860)
      - Chapter XI, "Vorüberziehende Wolke," draft, mimeograph (Box 35, Folder 861)
        See also: Box 58, folders 1430-31
      - "Inhaltsverzeichnis und Entstehungs- bericht," draft, typescript (Box 35, Folder 862)
      - "Entstehungsbericht," page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 863)
      - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 864)
      - Draft of complete work, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 865-68)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 869)
        See also: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1799
      - "Für den Schutzumschlag der Schuldlosen, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 870)
      - Book reviews, 1951-74, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 871)
      - Critical synopsis, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 872)
      - French dramatization ( Les Irresponsables ) by Andrée R. Picard, draft, typescript, photocopy (Box 35, Folder 873)
      - Dramatized radio commentary ( Tanz zur Hölle--Irrweg in den Elfenbeinturm ), by Clemens Goldberg
        - Script, typescript, photocopy, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 874)
        - Cassette tapes, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 875)
    - Sonja oder ueber unsere Kraft
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 876)
    - Tagebuch in Briefen an Ea von Allesch
      - Photocopy of original correspondence (Box 35, Folder 877)
      - Photocopy of original correspondence (Box 36, Folder 878)
      - Transcription and annotations by H. F. Broch de Rothermann, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 879-81)
      - Transcription and annotations by H. F. Broch de Rothermann, photocopy (Box 36, Folder 882-84)
      - Excerpts made by H. F. Broch de Rothermann, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 885)
    - Der Tod des Vergil
      - Research notes, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 886)
      - Early studies
        - "Die Heimkehr der Vergil," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 887)
          See also: Box 51, folder 1162
        - Untitled version (44 leaves), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 888)
        - "Ur-Vergil," holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 889)
        - "Erzählung vom Tode," typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 890)
        - Untitled version (166 leaves), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 891-92)
      - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected ("Kahler" working copy), n.d. (Box 37, Folder 893-99)
      - Draft A, corrections, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 900)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected ("Arendt" copy) (Box 37, Folder 901-02)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected ("Arendt" copy) (Box 38, Folder 903-07)
      - Draft B, bound, typescript, carbon ("Staudinger" copy), 1945 (Box 38, Folder 908)
      - Draft fragments
        - Unidentified pages, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 909)
        - Unidentified pages (nonconsecutive leaves - early), n.d. (Box 38, Folder 910)
        - Unidentified pages (nonconsecutive leaves - late), n.d. (Box 38, Folder 911)
      - Publisher's prospectus and subscription form (Box 38, Folder 912)
      - Subscription list, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 913)
      - Book reviews, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 914-16)
      - Book reviews, 1946-84, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 917-23)
        See also: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1800
      - Various commentaries, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 924)
      - English translation by Jean Starr Untermeyer
        See also: Correspondence, Box 20, folders 622-46
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 925-28)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 929-30)
        - Draft B, typescript, bound, carbon, corrected, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 931)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 932-36)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 937)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 938)
        - Translator's note, various drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 41, Folder 939-40)
        - Transcription of reading from Broch's The Death of Virgil made on tape recording at the Library of Congress by JSU, typescript, 1962 (Box 41, Folder 941)
    - Die unbekannte Grösse
      - Vorbemerkung, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 942)
      - Grundzüge zum Roman, typescript and carbon (Box 41, Folder 943)
      - Draft A, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 41, Folder 944)
      - Draft A, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 41, Folder 945)
      - Draft B, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 41, Folder 946)
      - Serial version in Vossische Zeitung, Berlin, copy 1, 1933 Sep-Oct (Box 41, Folder 947)
      - Serial version in Vossische Zeitung, Berlin, copy 2, 1933 Sep-Oct (Box 41, Folder 948)
      - Serial version in Vossische Zeitung, Berlin, copy 3, incomplete, 1933 Sep (Box 41, Folder 949)
      - Page proofs, bound, corrected, copy 1 (Box 42, Folder 950)
      - Page proofs, bound, corrected, copy 2 (Box 42, Folder 951)
      - Entwürfe für die Illustration zu Hermann Broch Die unbekannte Grösse: Federzeichnungen von Bettina Bauer Ehrlich, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 952)
      - Advertisements, 1933, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 953)
      - Book reviews, 1932-35, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 954)
      - Film dramatization
        - Vorbemerkung, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 955)
        - Script, "Das unbekannte X: Der Film einer physikalischen Theorie," bound, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 42, Folder 956)
  - PLAYS
    - Aus der Luft gegriffen oder Die Geschäfte des Baron Laborde